Right
そうだ
My father
私の父
Has more words for you
まだ言いたいことがある
Yue'er
月
I'm afraid
私は恐れています
I won't live to see Your Highness
殿下を待てない
Father
お父さん
Tell Your Highness for me
あなたが私の代わりに殿下に伝えてください
This northern expedition
今回の北伐
Could not press on
勢いに乗れなかった
To reclaim the land
神州を取り戻す
Then we should
それならそうすべきだ
Follow my original plan
私の元の方針を守る
Use Beiyu Pass as a springboard
北域の関を踏み台にして
Actively prepare
積極的に準備する
And wait for the right time
時を待つ
Yue'er
月
I have something
私は同じものを持っています
To give to Your Highness
殿下にお渡しください
General Zu Kun has something to give me
祖坤将軍にはまだ私に渡すものがあります
This
これ
Is soil from less than two hundred li from Yong'an
永安からわずか二百里の土地です
Please take it back, Your Highness
殿下持ち帰ってください
Let the court's
朝廷に上がらせる
Nobles
諸公卿
Take a good look at this homeland
この故郷をじっくり見てごらん
The court
朝廷たち
The court has its own considerations
朝廷には朝廷の考えがある
Has difficulties and hardships
困難や苦しみがある
Various concerns
さまざまな懸念
I know
私は知っています
Heaven did not grant more years
年を取らないようだ
Only leaving endless regret
空しく長く恨む
Brothers of the volunteer army
義勇軍の兄弟たちへ
The war is over
戦いはすでに終わった
I will arrange places for you
私はあなたたちに行き先を手配します
Those willing to take up arms
ナイフを持つことをいとわない
Will join the army
軍に編入する
Those willing to take money
お金をもらいたい人
I will send people to take you to Liangzhou
私は人を派遣して皆さんを梁州まで案内し落ち着けるようにします
I'll follow Your Highness
俺は殿下とやる
Follow Your Highness
殿下とやる
Good
いい
From today
今日から
I will form you into a separate army
私はあなたたちを別々に一つの軍隊に編成します
Led by General Zhu
朱将軍が統率する
Yes
はい
Since this army
この軍隊である以上
Was built in the north
北の地に建てられた
I give you the name
私はあなたたちに名前を与えます
Beishuo Army
北朔軍
At your command
命令を聞く
Here
で
Brother-in-law
義兄
Urgent edict from the Ministry of War
兵部の急令
What is it?
どうしたの
Father is gravely ill
父は重い病気です
Summoning me to return to the capital immediately
私を召してすぐに京に帰らせよ
At this time
このとき
Go investigate the situation again
もう一度様子を探りに行ってみてください
Call Zhu Yuanzhi to discuss together
朱元之を呼んで一緒に相談する
Yes
はい
All investigated
全部はっきりさせた